So, in my case,
私が選んだのは
one of the use cases I picked was demand forecasting in manufacturing.
製造業の需要予測です
So, first, we cast it as a machine learning problem and asked what is being predicted.
これを機械学習の問題に当てはめ 何を予測するか考えます
Well, because we're doing demand forecasting in manufacturing,
製造業の需要予測ですから
what is being predicted is how many units of widgets X should be manufactured this month.
予測するのは 部品Xの今月の製造量です
For example, if you're making phone display panels,
たとえば 電話のディスプレイパネルなら
how many phone display panels of
4インチと6インチスクリーン用をそれぞれ
a four inch screen or a six inch screen should we manufacture this month?
今月中に何個製造すればいいのか
So that is what is being predicted.
こうしたことについての予測が行われます
what data do we need?
どんなデータが必要かです
Well, if you want to be predicting how many units
製品を何個製造すればよいか予測したい場合
of that widget to manufacture, what data do we need?
どんなデータが必要ですか？
Well, we need historical data on the number of units sold,
これには売上個数の履歴が必要でしょう
how many units did we sell last month,
先月は何個売れたか
how many units did we sell the month before, et cetera.
その前の月は何個売れたかなどです
We also need to know the price that it was sold at,
販売価格も知る必要があります
the number of units that were returned,
返品個数や
the price of any competitor product out there,
他社製品の販売価格
and the number of units of all items that use widgets X.
部品Xを使用する製品の数
So if you're making phone display screens,
電話のディスプレイを製造している場合
how many smartphones are sold regardless of
使用しているディスプレイパネルや 自社他社製品を問わず
which display panel they carried or whether it was ours or our competitors?
すべてのスマートフォンの売上台数が 必要です
We will also need other data like economic figures,
加えて経済統計などのデータや
customer confidence, interest rate,
顧客の信頼性や金利情報
what happened this month,
去年はどうだったかなども
last year et cetera.
知っておく必要があるでしょう
The second framing is as a software problem.
2番目に ソフトウェアの問題として考えます
What is the API of the service?
サービスのAPIは？
Well, the method in the API could be predicted demand,
APIのメソッドは予測需要かもしれませんが
and what does it take?
入力には何が必要ですか？
The inputs might be the widget ID and the month that we want to do this prediction for,
入力は部品IDや予測したい月などです
with the default value for the month being the current month.
月のデフォルトは今月です
Notice that in this API,
このAPIでは
we are only asking for the widget ID and the time.
部品IDと期間のみが必要です
We are not asking for
機械学習モデルが必要とするような
all those other ancillary data that our machine learning model needed.
他の多くの補助データは不要です
We're not asking the end user to give us how many smartphone units were sold last month.
ユーザーに先月のスマートフォンの 売上台数を求める必要はありません
That is something that we would have to collect ourselves.
自分たちで収集するからです
Next part of the framing as a software problem is who's going to use the service.
次は 誰のためのサービスかを考えます
And because is the demand forecasting thing,
需要を予測しているため
we might think that the users might be product managers,
ユーザーは製品マネージャーや
might be logistics managers, et cetera.
物流マネージャーです
How are they doing it today?
今まではどうしていたのでしょう？
They examined trends of phone sales,
電話の売上台数や
overall economy, trade publications,
経済全般また業界誌などの傾向から
and they somehow make a decision.
どうにか決定していたのでしょう
The third framing is as a data problem.
3番目に データの問題として考えます
So what kind of data do we need to collect?
どのようなデータが必要ですか？
The things that we need to collect,
集めるのは トレーニングのためのデータですが
but for also for prediction,
予測のためにも データが必要です
that we can expect the end user to give us.
ユーザーから得られるものを除く すべてのデータを集めます
So what data do we need to collect?
どんなデータを集めますか？
We need to collect the economic data, the competitor data,
経済データや競争相手のデータ
the industry data, data from our company itself.
業界のデータや自社データなどでしょう
And what data do we need to analyze?
分析すべきデータは？
Well, we need to analyze all these datasets so that we can craft
これらすべてのデータセットを分析します
features that our experts are looking at today from this data,
そしてエキスパートが注目している 特徴を作成し
and we need to take those features and use them as inputs to our model.
モデルに入力します
And what is our reaction?
では反応は？
How do we react to a prediction of demand?
需要の予測にどのように反応しますか？
One way that we could do reaction might
1つの方法は
be that if we predicted that demand is going to increase,
需要の増加が予測されたら
we automatically go ahead and put out
自動的に発注し
orders to our suppliers for more of the things that they provide to us.
供給先に部品を もっと製造するように依頼することです
So the reaction might be automatic.
つまり反応を自動化するのです